Guide to the Arthur Davison Ficke Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1895-1959; Series II; 9.75; (25 boxes)
  - ARTHUR DAVISON FICKE
    - Poetry
      - "Poem to Miss G. Brown": holograph, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 983)
      - "Poem to Miss Lamb": holograph, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 984)
      - "A Poem to Miss Millay on Reading a History of Geometry": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 985)
      - [Poems written to John Cowper Powys]: "Mr. Powys Craft", "Epistle to Johannes...", "The Tadpole", "Afternoon Argument", and "To a Mystical Essayist", holograph and typescript, original (Box 34, Folder 986)
      - "Pome": holograph, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 987)
      - "Pome": holograph, n.d.
      - "Pome": holograph, n.d.
      - "Pome": holograph, n.d.
      - "Pome": holograph, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 988)
      - "Pome": holograph, n.d.
      - "Pome": holograph, n.d.
      - "Pome": holograph, n.d.
      - "Pome": holograph and typescript, 1932 (Box 34, Folder 989)
        With a clipping.
      - "Pome": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 990)
      - "Pome": typescript, original, n.d.
      - "Pome About a Great Poet and His Girl": typescript, original (Box 34, Folder 991)
      - "Pome for Mr. Devoe on Labor Day in the Year of Our Lord 1944": typescript, original, corrected (Box 34, Folder 992)
      - "Pome in Two Stanzas": holograph, n.d.
      - "Pome on Nice Girls": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 993)
      - "Pome To A Very Modern Young Lady": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 994)
      - "Pome to the Ineffectual Murderess": typescript, original, with sketches, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 995)
      - "Pome Words Without Music to Miss G. Brown": holograph, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 996)
      - "The Pope's Daughter": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 997)
      - "Portrait": printed version (12 copies), 1939 (Box 34, Folder 998)
      - "Portrait of Commisar Molitoff": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 999)
      - "Portrait by Yeisho": typescript, carbon, corrected, annotated, signed, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1000)
      - "Prayer in the Autumn Days": typescript, original, corrected, 1945 Sep 30 (Box 34, Folder 1001)
      - "Prayer to the Lord Allmighty in May": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1002)
      - "Release": holograph, written to Alan Devoe, 1942 Feb 21 (Box 34, Folder 1003)
      - "A Retrospect on the Lindbergh Episode": typescript, carbon (Box 34, Folder 1004)
      - "Return from Southern Lands": holograph, corrected (Box 34, Folder 1005)
      - "The Return to Stratford": holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1006)
      - "The Revolt of Uncle Peter": printed version, 1939 Oct (Box 34, Folder 1007)
      - "A Rhymed Alphabet": typescript, original, and typescript, carbon (2 copies) (Box 34, Folder 1008)
      - "Seranade Across Silence": printed version, 1927 Oct 10 (Box 34, Folder 1009)
      - "Silly-Sallies": typescript, original, and carbon, corrected, 1944-45 (Box 34, Folder 1010)
      - "Sing a Song of...": typescript, original, corrected, 1945 Sep 3 (Box 34, Folder 1011)
      - "The Solitary Last Gentleman": holograph and typescript, original, corrected (Box 34, Folder 1012)
      - "Some Limmericks": typescript, carbon, 1927 (Box 34, Folder 1013)
      - "Song in an Ancient Manner": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1014)
      - "Song Overheard in a Dream": three drafts, holograph, typescript, original and carbon, 1945 Jul-Sep (Box 34, Folder 1015)
        With holograph note by Gladys Brown Ficke.
      - "The Spirit World": [written with Floyd Dell], typescript, original and printed version, 1929 (Box 34, Folder 1016)
      - "Still Life": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1017)
      - "Summer Evening in Rhapsody": song lyric, typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1018)
      - "A Threnody in the Nudist Season": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1019)
      - "To a Former Governor": printed version, 1932 Aug 23 (Box 34, Folder 1020)
      - "To a Poet on his Fiftieth Birthday": holograph, corrected [written for Witter Bynner], n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1021)
      - "To Dan'l": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1022)
      - "To George Meredith": holograph, typescript, original, corrected, and typescript, carbon, corrected, 1941 Oct 7 (Box 34, Folder 1023)
      - "To Mr. Devoe, A Token of Thanks for the Loan of the Complete Works of Dr. Swift": typescript, original, annotated, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1024)
      - "To My Aunt Ella": holograph, 1890 (Box 34, Folder 1025)
      - "To My Sisters": typescript, original, corrected, 1945 Oct 2 (Box 34, Folder 1026)
      - "To the Dial": holograph, n.d.
      - "To the Young": printed version, 1940 Apr (Box 34, Folder 1027)
      - "The Towers of Babel": printed version, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1028)
      - "Tuberculosis Sanatorium": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1029)
      - "Two Landscapes": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 34, Folder 1030)
      - "Two-Score and Ten": typescript, carbon, annotated [sent to Floyd Dell] (Box 34, Folder 1031)
      - "U.S. Proposes to Ban Submarines": typescript, original, and printed version, 1928 Feb 13 (Box 34, Folder 1032)
      - "Unconditional Surrender": typescript, original, and printed version, 1928 Feb 13 (Box 34, Folder 1033)
      - "The Unicorn and the Honey Bear": typescript, corrected (Box 34, Folder 1034)
      - "Upper Hudson Valley": typescript, carbon, and typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 34, Folder 1035)
      - "Vision Seen on Waking": typescript, carbon, corrected, annotated, 1940 (Box 34, Folder 1036)
      - "A Visit to the Drugstore": holograph, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1037)
      - "Weekend Hostess, Monday Evening": [by Anne Knish] typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 34, Folder 1038)
      - "When I Consider...": typescript, carbon, 1943 Apr 6 (Box 34, Folder 1039)
      - "When a Literary Gentleman Submits his Effusion to a Critical Poetic Lady": printed version [written with Edna St. Vincent Millay], n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1040)
      - "Women": typescript, carbon, annotated [sent to Floyd Dell], n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1041)
      - "Word Without Letter": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1042)
      - "The World of the Hills": song lyrics, typescript, original, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1043)
      - Untitled poems: holograph, and typescript, original (Box 34, Folder 1044-1045)
    - Miscellaneous Writings
      - Articles and Essays
        - "Additional notes on Llewelyn Powys": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1046)
        - "All Dog Owners are Crazy": correspondence, 1939 (Box 35, Folder 1047)
        - "Am I Right in Thinking That-": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1048)
        - "Americanism": printed version, 1936 Nov (Box 35, Folder 1049)
        - "Arthur Davison Ficke on the Modern View of Poetry": printed version (2 copies), 1915 Aug 14 (Box 35, Folder 1050)
        - "Aspects of Chinese Painting": printed version, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1051)
        - "Cambodian Sunset": printed version, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1052)
        - "Censorship": printed version, 1930 Feb (Box 35, Folder 1053)
        - "Chats on Japanese Prints": notes, holograph and plates (Box 35, Folder 1054)
        - Composition for Violin and Cello: typescript, original, annotated and corrected [Written with Eric Lundgren], 1937 Dec (Box 35, Folder 1055)
        - "[Five Requisites for Happiness...]": holograph, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1056)
        - "Gem-Point": holograph and typescript, original, corrected (Box 35, Folder 1057)
        - "The Geography of France": holograph, corrected, 1930 Feb (Box 35, Folder 1058)
        - "The Great Hardhack Detective Story or [How] Would You Like It": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1059)
        - "Honorary Degree for Herr von Beethoven": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1060)
        - "Interview de Luxe with Edna St. Vincent Millay": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1061)
        - "It Depends on the Definition": corrected proof and printed version, 1942 (Box 35, Folder 1062)
        - "Modern Irish Plays from Two Points of View": printed version, [ca. 1921] (Box 35, Folder 1063)
        - "Modern Tendencies in Poetry": printed version, 1916 Sep (Box 35, Folder 1064)
        - "Mr. Milton's Paradise": printed version, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1065)
        - "The Name and Nature of A. E. Houseman": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 35, Folder 1066)
        - "The Nature of Beauty": notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1067)
        - [Newspaper parodies]: typescript, carbon, annotated and corrected, 1933-36 (Box 35, Folder 1068)
        - "Note": preface for Collected Sonnets by Edna St. Vincent Millay, typescript, carbon, 1941 Sep 4 (Box 35, Folder 1069)
          With holograph notes by Arthur Davison Ficke and Edna St. Vincent Millay.
        - "A Note on the Poetry of Robinson Jeffers": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1070)
        - "A Note on the Psychology of Arrow Making": typescript, original, 1932 Apr 3 (Box 35, Folder 1071)
        - [Notes]: holograph, with a clipping, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1072)
        - Notes on [Yone] Noguchi, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1072a)
        - "Notes for a Young Man": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1073)
        - "Notes on Edgar Lee Masters 1938-9": typescript, original, corrected, 1939 Apr 31 (Box 35, Folder 1074)
        - "Of Man and Life": printed version, 1941 (Box 35, Folder 1075)
        - "A Poet also Looks at a Companinate Marriage": printed version, 1928 Feb 8 (Box 35, Folder 1076)
        - "The Poetry and Prose of Francis Thompson": printed version (part 1), 1913 (Box 35, Folder 1077)
        - "Points for Beginner Poets": printed version, 1935 Sep (Box 35, Folder 1078)
        - "Present State of Poetry": printed version, 1911 Sep (Box 35, Folder 1079)
        - "The Prints of Kwaigetsudo": printed version, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1080)
        - "Recollections of Kuno Franke": printed version, 1930 (Box 35, Folder 1081)
        - "Reflections of a Bible-Reader": printed version, [ca. 1922] (Box 35, Folder 1082)
        - "The Sense of Beauty": notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1083)
        - "Sensual Aesthetic Theory": notes, holograph, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1084)
        - "The Shiek of the Pryamids": printed version, 1899 Jun (Box 35, Folder 1085)
        - "The Spread of Modernist Art": printed version, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1086)
        - "Threnody in the Hunting Season": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1087)
        - "Traitors to the Agrarian Culture": typescript, original, and typescript, carbon, corrected, three draft (Box 35, Folder 1088)
        - "The Three Ways of Going Mad, Art- Religion-Insanity": holograph and typescript, original, corrected (Box 35, Folder 1089)
        - "Twelve Short Essays": contents page, typescript, annotated, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1090)
        - "The Value of Non-Virtue to the Woman Artist": printed version, 1933 Jun (Box 35, Folder 1091)
        - "What Results Do You want to Produce": printed version, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1092)
      - Autobiographical Writings
        - [Autobiography]: holograph and typescript, original, corrected, [ca. 1935] (Box 35, Folder 1093)
        - "Ether": typescript, original, 1918 (Box 35, Folder 1094)
        - "The Great River; A Fictitious Biography of My Mother": Chapter one, typescript, original, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1095)
        - "Ignominious Episodes": holograph and typescript, original, corrected (Box 35, Folder 1096)
        - "Letters Across a Mountain": graph and typescript [written with Floyd Dell], 1923 (Box 35, Folder 1097)
        - "Mirage of Childhood": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1098)
        - "Notes From the Diary of a Tuberculosis Patient": holograph, 1934 Nov (Box 35, Folder 1099)
        - "Notes From the Diary of a Tuberculosis Patient": printed version (2 copies), 1934 Nov (Box 35, Folder 1100)
        - "Notes From a Hospital": holograph, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1101)
        - "Portraits of My Friends, An Autobiography": holograph and typescript, original, corrected (Box 35, Folder 1102)
        - "The Psychology of Pulmonary Tuberculosis as Seen by a Layman": typescript, original, corrected, first draft, [1932] (Box 35, Folder 1103)
        - "The Psychology of Pulmonary Tuberculosis as Seen by a Layman": revised draft, 1932 (Box 35, Folder 1104)
        - "Seven Years": Part 1, typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1105)
        - "Seven Years": Part 2, typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1106)
        - "What I Remember. An Autobiography": Chapters I-IV, holograph and typescript (Box 36, Folder 1107)
      - Lectures
        - "Beginning of a Lecture on Poetry I-II": holograph, and typescript, original, corrected (Box 36, Folder 1108)
        - "Beginning of a Lecture on Poetry III-V": holograph and typescript, original and carbon (Box 36, Folder 1109)
          With correspondence from The Left, 1931 May.
        - "Certain Aspects of the Theory of Poetry": sketch for Amherst lecture, holograph, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1110)
        - The Problem of Censorship: printed version, read before The Contemporary Club, 1922 Mar 20 (Box 36, Folder 1111)
      - Reviews
        - "Among Chinese and Japanese Poets": review of Lotus and Chrysanthemum, ed. by Joseph Lewis French, typescript, carbon (Box 36, Folder 1112)
          Related Archival Materials note
          See also: "Oriental Poets", Box 36, folder 1123
        - "Cool Intelligent Astringence": review of Selected Letters of Edwin Arlington Robinson, printed version, 1940 Feb 25 (Box 36, Folder 1113)
        - "A Divine Visionary": review of Selections from the Symbolic Poems of William Blake, by Frederick A. Pierce, printed version, 1915 Oct 14 (Box 36, Folder 1114)
        - "Floyd Dell's Autobiography": review, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1115)
        - "G. C. Cook: Mad Humanist": review of The Road to the Temple by Susan Glaspell, printed version, 1927 (Box 36, Folder 1116)
        - "The Harding Memorial": review of The President's Daughter by Nan Britton, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1117)
        - "Last Days of the Russian Aristocracy Pictured in the Novel": review of If Today Have No Tomorrow by Olive Gilbreath, printed version, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1118)
        - "The Light Ironic Humor of Oscar Wilde...": printed version, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1119)
        - "The Luminous Chinese Sage": review of The Way of Life, According to Laotzu..., by Witter Bynner, printed version, 1946 Apr (Box 36, Folder 1120)
        - "Major Prophet": review of The Living Thoughts of Emerson, printed version, 1940 Apr 21 (Box 36, Folder 1121)
        - "Mrs. Warren's Profession": printed version, 1916 Dec 1 (Box 36, Folder 1122)
        - "Oriental Poets": review of Lotus and Chrysanthemum, printed version, 1928 (Box 36, Folder 1123)
        - Our Family: by Adet and Anor Lei, printed version, 1939 Jun (Box 36, Folder 1124)
        - [Review of Amherst Literary Magazine, printed version], 1928 Dec (Box 36, Folder 1125)
        - "Seattle's New Repertory Company": printed version, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1126)
        - "Translating the Untranslatable": reviews of Japanese Poetry by Curtis H. Page and The Temple and Other Poems, translated by Arthur Waley, printed version (Box 36, Folder 1127)
      - Short stories
        - "The Ant and His Uncle": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 36, Folder 1128)
        - "Bernard the Bright": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1129)
        - "The Birthday Celebration of Professor Naumanstark": typescript, carbon, [ca. 1940] (Box 36, Folder 1130)
        - "The Brother's Sister": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1131)
        - "Call Me Stanley": correspondence, 1954-55 (Box 36, Folder 1132)
        - "The Cat of Mongatola Beach": notes, holograph, and typescript (Box 36, Folder 1133)
        - "The Cat of Mongatola Beach": typescript, original, corrected, and holograph (Box 36, Folder 1134)
          With p. 1-2, typescript, original.
        - "The Cat of Mongatola Beach": correspondence, 1933-34 (Box 36, Folder 1135)
        - "Collector of Violins": typescript, original, corrected (2 copies), n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1136)
          With a note to Eric Lundgren from ADF, and a note by Arthur Gingrich and David Smart.
        - "The Colt Named Dan'l": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1137)
        - [Contents page for an untitled collection of short stories]: typescript, annotated, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1138)
        - "Fable of Gadgets in Monkeyland": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 36, Folder 1139)
        - "Fable of the Choosen Monkeys": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1140)
        - "Four Tons of Sardines": typescript, original, corrected, and typescript, carbon, corrected (2 copies) (Box 36, Folder 1141)
        - "The Frozen Mammoth": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1142)
        - "The Gypsy Bear": first draft, typescript, carbon, corrected and final draft, typescript, carbon (Box 36, Folder 1143)
        - "A God of One's Own": typescript, carbon, signed, seventh draft, [ca. 1939] (Box 36, Folder 1144)
        - "Grandma Baumgartner Detective": outlines, holograph, and typescript, original, corrected (Box 36, Folder 1145)
        - "The Images of the Ancestors": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1146)
          With list of magazine submissions.
        - "The Lady-Bug of God": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1147)
        - "The Metamorphosis of Momo:" typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 1148)
        - Mrs. Morton of Mexico series. "A Candle for St. Christopher": printed version, 1935 Mar (Box 36, Folder 1149)
        - Mrs. Morton of Mexico series. "The Portrait of Mrs. Morton": printed version (2 copies), 1936 Dec (Box 36, Folder 1150)
        - Mrs. Morton of Mexico series. "Mrs. Morton Buys a fish": printed version, 1937 Jun (Box 36, Folder 1151)
        - Mrs. Morton of Mexico series. "The Brother of Mrs. Morton": printed version, 1937 Aug (Box 36, Folder 1152)
        - Mrs. Morton of Mexico series. "The Burro of Chapala": printed version, 1937 Dec (Box 36, Folder 1153)
        - Mrs. Morton of Mexico series. "All Roads to Graves are Dusty": printed version (2 copies), 1938 Mar (Box 36, Folder 1154)
        - Mrs. Morton of Mexico series. "The Conquest of Mexico": printed version, 1938 Apr (Box 36, Folder 1155)
        - Mrs. Morton of Mexico series. "Mrs. Morton's Enemy": printed version, 1938 May (Box 36a, Folder 1156)
        - Mrs. Morton of Mexico series. "The Twenty-First Lion": printed version, 1938 Jun (Box 36a, Folder 1157)
        - Mrs. Morton of Mexico series. "The Apotheosis of Mrs. Morton": printed version, 1938 Jul (Box 36a, Folder 1158)
        - Mrs. Morton of Mexico series. Reviews, in scrapbook, 1936-38 (Box 36a, Folder 1158a)
        - "The Peanut Artist": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 36a, Folder 1159)
        - "The Presence of a Lady": typescript, original, corrected, and typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 36a, Folder 1160)
        - "Strollers at a Fair": typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 36a, Folder 1161)
        - "Subway Cage": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 36a, Folder 1162)
          With list of magazines.
        - "That Does Not Sound Like Patrick Dugan": typescript, original, corrected (Box 36a, Folder 1163)
        - "The Tomb of His Ancestors": typescript, original, corrected., n.d. (Box 36a, Folder 1164)
        - "Tribute to Greatness": typescript, original, corrected, 1941 (Box 36a, Folder 1165)
        - "The True and Only History of the Death of Don Juan": holograph and typescript, corrected (Box 36a, Folder 1166)
          With Epigrams of Love, Life, and Laughter by Anatole France, 1924.
        - The Virtue of the Comtesse de Verre": typescript, original, corrected, 1940 (Box 36a, Folder 1167)
        - "The Vow of Asinuous": typescript, carbon, 1895 Mar 25 (Box 36a, Folder 1168)
        - "The Woodpecker of Middlesex County": typescript, corrected, 1937-38, n.d. (Box 36a, Folder 1169)
          With 2 clippings.
  - GLADYS BROWN FICKE
    - Articles and Essays
      - "An Artist Looks at Psychoanalysis": final draft, typescript, original, and typescript, carbon, corrected, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 1170)
      - "Arthur Davison Ficke and his Friends": typescript, carbon, corrected, [ca. 1949] (Box 37, Folder 1171)
      - "Arthur Davison Ficke and his Friends": printed version, 1949 Jan (Box 37, Folder 1172)
      - "Beatnicks": notes, holograph, and typescript (Box 37, Folder 1173)
      - "Day-dreaming and Non-Objective Painting": typescript, original, and typescript, carbon (Box 37, Folder 1174)
      - "Dialogue in the Singular": typescript, original, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1175)
      - "Genius vs. Society": typescript, original, and typescript, carbon (Box 37, Folder 1176)
      - "Grief": typescript, original, and typescript, carbon, 1946 Feb (Box 37, Folder 1177)
      - "Herbert von Karajan and the Philharmonic Orchestra of London": typescript, original, corrected (Box 37, Folder 1178)
      - "[Letters on Arthur Davison Ficke]": holograph and typescript, original (Box 37, Folder 1179)
      - "[Made at Lake Chapala, Mexico]": holograph, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1180)
      - "Propaganda and Art": typescript, original, corrected (Box 37, Folder 1181)
      - "The Story of the Letters": typescript, original, corrected, 1960 Apr 17-18 (Box 37, Folder 1182)
      - "[Styles in Art]": typescript, original and typescript, carbon, corrected, 1956-64, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1183)
        With notes and clippings.
      - "Work": typescript, original, corrected, and typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 37, Folder 1184)
      - Untitled essay: holograph, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1185)
    - Books
      - "Arthur Davison Ficke: A Biography"
        - Notes: holograph and typescript (Box 37, Folder 1186)
        - Book I, Chapters I-XI: typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1187-1197)
        - Book Two, Chapters 1-7: typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 1198-1204)
        - Book Two, Chapters 8-12: typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1205-1216)
        - Book Two, p. 1475-1494: third version, typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1217)
        - Book Two, p. 1475-1494: [third draft?]: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1218-1219)
        - Unidentified draft: p.1-11, typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1220)
        - Unidentified draft: typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1221-1223)
      - "The Final Beauty"
        - Chapters 1-10: typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 1224-1225)
        - Chapters 11-32: typescript, original, corrected, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1226-1230)
      - "Girl-Child, Nineteen Seventeen"
        - Notes: holograph, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1231)
        - Outline sketch: typescript, annotated, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1232)
      - "The Poetry and Philosophy of Chinese Landscape Painting"
        - Notes: holograph and typescript, and printed material, 1945-59, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1233-1235)
        - Introduction: original draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 1236)
        - Original draft: typescript, original and carbon, corrected, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 1237-39)
          With holograph notes.
        - Incomplete draft: typescript, original, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1240)
        - Fragments: holograph, typescript, original and carbon, corrected, [ca. 1958], n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1241-43)